Guide to the Charles Nagel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Topical Files, 1880-1939; Series II; 5' (12 boxes, 1 folio)
  - Saint Louis, Missouri
    - Activities and organizations, 1907-1939, undated (Box 62, Folder 87-89)
    - Defender's Plan, 1936, 1937, undated (Box 62, Folder 90-91)
  - Saint Louis and Alabama Coal Syndicate, 1923-1926, undated (Box 63, Folder 92-94)
  - Sealing controversy
    - General, 1904-1922, undated (Box 63, Folder 95-101)
      General
    - Postcards, photographs, and clippings, 1910-1922 (Box 64, Folder 102-106)
  - Speeches
    - Chronological, 1890-1895 (Box 64, Folder 107-113)
    - Chronological, 1896-1911 (Box 65, Folder 114-131)
    - Chronological, 1912-1939 (Box 66, Folder 132-157)
    - Topical, undated (Box 67, Folder 158-167)
    - Notes, undated (Box 67, Folder 168-174)
  - Thomas Jefferson National Expansion Memorial Association, 1936-1939, undated (Box 67, Folder 175)
  - United States and German Mixed Claims Commission, 1916-1928, undated (Box 68, Folder 176-179)
  - United States Chamber of Commerce, 1923-1929, undated (Box 68, Folder 180-182)
    See also: box 3, Folders 38-49
  - Washington University, 1899-1929, undated (Box 68, Folder 183)
  - World War I, 1915-1918, undated (Box 68, Folder 184-186)
  - World War II, 1932-1939, undated (Box 68, Folder 187-188)
  - Alaskan maps, 1908, undated (Box 69)
    Folio
  - Passports, 1914 (Box 69)
- Letterbooks and Scrapbooks (HM Film 94)
  Nagel, Charles, 1849-1940
  Letterbooks, 1877-1922; scrapbooks, 1909-1910 53v.
  Microfilm. New Haven, Yale University Library, 1979. 33 reels
  - Letterbooks 1 and 2, 1877 June 2-1881 December 3 (Box 1)
  - Letterbook 3, 1881 December 2-1883 January 28 (Box 2)
  - Letterbook 4, 1883 January 25-July 16 (Box 2)
  - Letterbooks 5 and 6, 1883 July 17-1885 February 27 (Box 3)
  - Letterbooks 7 and 8, 1885 February 27-December 1 (Box 4)
  - Letterbook 9, 1886 December 4-1887 July 12 (Box 5)
  - Letterbook 10, 1887 July 13-1888 April 20 (Box 5)
  - Letterbook 10, 1888 April 20-November 27 (Box 6)
  - Letterbook 11, 1888 November 27-1889 November 18 (Box 6)
  - Letterbook 11, 1889 November 18-1890 January 23 (Box 7)
  - Letterbook 12, 1890 January 24-October 10 (Box 7)
  - Letterbook 13, 1890 October 10-1891 September 25 (Box 8)
  - Letterbook 14, 1891 September 25-1892 September 30 (Box 9)
  - Letterbook 15, 1892 September 30-1892 December 27 (Box 9)
  - Letterbook 15, 1892 December 27-1893 October 27 (Box 10)
  - Letterbook 16, 1893 October 27-1894 June 1 (Box 10)
  - Letterbook 16, 1894 June 1-September 17 (Box 11)
  - Letterbook 17, 1893 May 3-1899 May 3 (Box 11)
  - Letterbook 18, 1894 September 17-1895 June 21 (Box 11)
  - Letterbook 19 and 20, 1895 June 22-1901 May 25 (Box 12)
  - Letterbook 21, 1896 April 24-1898 December 1 (Box 13)
  - Letterbook 22, 1898 December 2-1900 March 20 (Box 13)
  - Letterbook 22, 1900 March 20-September 4 (Box 14)
  - Letterbook 23, 1900 September 4-1901 July 11 (Box 14)
  - Letterbook 24, 1902 August 23-1904 February 15 (Box 15)
    [No index available]
  - Letterbook 25, 1907 February 4-1909 March 31 (Box 16)
  - Letterbooks 26 to 28, 1909 March 9-December 28 (Box 17)
  - Letterbooks 29 and 30, 1910 November 28-1911 March 21 (Box 18)
  - Letterbooks 31 and 32, 1911 March 21-July 6 (Box 19)
  - Letterbooks 33 and 34, 1911 July 7-December 30 (Box 20)
  - Letterbooks 35 and 36, 1911 December 30-1912 April 15 (Box 21)
  - Letterbooks 37 and 38, 1912 April 16-November 9 (Box 22)
  - Letterbooks 39 and 40, 1912 November 9-1913 March 4 (Box 23)
  - Letterbook 41, 1907 January 4-1907 September 20 (Box 23)
  - Letterbook 41?, 1913 March 28-1914 February 4 (Box 23)
  - Letterbook 42, 1914 February 5-1915 February 22 (Box 24)
  - Letterbooks 43, 1915 February 22-November 20 (Box 25)
  - Letterbook 45, 1916 May 9-1917 February 26 (Box 26)
  - Letterbook 46, 1917 February 27-1918 February 12 (Box 27)
  - Letterbook 47, 1918 February 13-1919 May 5 (Box 28)
  - Letterbook 48, 1919 May 7-1920 February 16 (Box 29)
  - Letterbook 49, 1920 February 16-December 4 (Box 30)
  - Letterbook 50, 1920 December 4-1921 August 11 (Box 31)
  - Letterbook 51, 1921 August 11-1922 June 28 (Box 32)
  - Scrapbooks 1 and 2 relating to Nagel's cabinet term, 1909-1910 (Box 33)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-031
  - Correspondence
    - Ahrens, Georg
      - 1926-1931, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
    - Nagel, Anne Shepley [wife]
      - 1907, 1909, 1915-1924, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-14)
  - Dedication of memorial for Anne Shepley Nagel, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Speech [by Nagel as president of St. Louis City Council], n.y. April 27 (Box 1, Folder 16)